Register of the Bonner Frank Fellers Papers, 1904-1997
Hoover Institution Archives
- Psychological Warfare File, 1947-1955. (Box 43-45)
  - Printed matter
    - 1951-1955 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Proposals, 1950-1952 (Folder 44: 6)
  - Speeches, 1947 (Folder 44: 7)
  - Writings by Fellers on psychological warfare campaigns conducted by the United States
    - Relating to Japan, circa 1950-1954. (Folder 44: 8-10)
      Incorporates "Report on Psychological Warfare against Japan, Southwest Pacific Areas, 1944-1945," 1946. Typescript draft with some holograph passages
    - Relating to the Soviet Union, circa 1950-1954. (Box-folder 45: 1-2)
      Holograph and typescript fragments
- Fellers Family File, 1937-1990. (Box 45)
  Correspondence, notes, and report, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence, 1937-1981
    - Dorothy Fellers, 1937-1981
      - General
        - Christmas cards, 1960-1980 (Folder 45: 3)
        - A-K, 1937-1976 (Folder 45: 4)
        - L-Z, 1945-1981 (Folder 45: 5)
      - Fellers, Bonner, 1944-1945 (Folder 45: 6)
      - Hunt, Frazier, Mr. and Mrs., undated. (Folder 45: 7)
      - Kasai, Jiuji, 1975-1977 (Folder 45: 8)
      - Rochford, Daniel, 1978-1980 (Folder 45: 9)
      - Toland, John, 1978-1981 (Folder 45: 10)
      - Trohan, Walter, 1950-1976 (Folder 45: 11)
    - Nancy Fellers Finch, 1957-1990
      - General
        - A-K, 1969-1990 (Folder 45: 12)
        - L-Z, 1957-1978 (Folder 45: 13)
      - Curtis, Kenneth I., 1975-1976 (Folder 45: 14)
      - Kasai, Jiuji, 1965-1981 (Folder 45: 15)
      - Rochford, Daniel, 1978-1983 (Folder 45: 16)
  - Notes on the life of Bonner Fellers by Dorothy Fellers and Nancy Fellers Finch, undated and 1975 (Folder 45: 17)
  - Report on the student experience of Nancy Fellers at Vassar College, compiled by Bonner and Dorothy Fellers, 1952 (Folder 45: 18)
- Albums, 1949-1963. (Box 46-50)
  Clippings, correspondence, photographs, printed matter, and speeches, arranged in two groups, alphabetically by publication or subject, or chronologically
  - By publication or subject, 1949-1952
    - American Mercury, 1952 (Folder 46: 1)
    - Collier's, 1950-1951 (Folder 46: 2)
    - Coronet, 1950 (Folder 46: 3)
    - Defense, 1949-1951 (Folder 46: 4)
    - Egypt, 1951 (Folder 46: 5)
    - The Freeman, 1950-1951 (Folder 46: 6)
    - Human Events, 1949-1952 (Folder 46: 7)
    - Speeches, 1950-1952 (Folder 46: 8)
    - Thought war, 1949-1950 (Folder 46: 9)
    - Veterans, 1950-1951 (Folder 46: 10)
  - By year, 1949-1963
    - 1949 (Folder 46: 11)
    - 1950 (Folder 46: 12-13)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 47: 1-2)
    - 1952 (Folder 47: 3)
    - 1953 (Folder 47: 4)
    - 1954 (Folder 47: 5)
    - 1955 (Folder 47: 6)
    - 1956 (Folder 47: 7)
    - 1957 (Folder 47: 8)
    - 1958 (Folder 47: 9)
    - 1959 (Folder 47: 10)
    - 1960 (Box-folder 48: 1-7)
    - 1961 (Folder 48: 8)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 49: 1-3)
    - 1962 (Folder 49: 4-6)
    - 1963 (Folder 49: 7-8)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 50: 1)
- Subject File II, 1904-1974. (Box 50-55)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and speeches, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Air power
    - 1947-1954 (Folder 50: 2)
    - 1955-1958 (Folder 50: 3)
  - Baudista, Mariano, undated (Folder 50: 4)
  - Boldyreff, Constantine W., 1953-1965 (Folder 50: 5)
  - ChinaHistory20th century, 1942-1972 (Folder 50: 6)
  - Clifford, Clark, 1968-1969 (Folder 50: 7)
  - Communism, 1950-1971 (Folder 50: 8)
  - CreteOccupation (1941-1945), undated (Folder 50: 9)
  - CzechoslovakiaIntervention (1968) (Folder 50: 10)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1970-1972 (Folder 50: 11)
  - Earlham College
    - 1948-1955 (Folder 50: 12)
    - 1956-1971 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Edison, Charles, 1969 (Folder 51: 2)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David
    - 1947-1954 (Folder 51: 3)
    - 1955-1971 (Folder 51: 4)
  - GermanyHistory20th century, 1943-1957 (Folder 51: 5)
  - Gold, 1957-1972 (Folder 51: 6)
  - Groves, Leslie R., 1952-1972 (Folder 51: 7)
  - Herbert Hoover Presidential Library, 1971-1973 (Folder 51: 8)
  - Hirohito, Emperor of Japan, 1947-1971 (Folder 51: 9)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1932-1974 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Hunt, Frazier, 1967 (Folder 52: 2)
  - Internal securityUnited StatesHistory20th century, 1954-1955 (Folder 52: 3)
  - JapanHistory20th century
    - 1930-1947 (Folder 52: 4)
    - 1948-1970 (Folder 52: 5)
  - Kasai, Jiuji, 1963 (Folder 52: 6)
  - Kimmel, Husband, undated (Folder 52: 7)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1970-1971 (Folder 52: 8)
  - Korean War (1950-1953) (Folder 52: 9)
  - MacArthur, Douglas
    - 1933-1936 (Folder 52: 10)
    - 1942-1944 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - 1945-1949 (Folder 53: 2)
    - 1950-1954 (Folder 53: 3)
    - 1955-1958 (Folder 53: 4)
    - 1964 (Folder 53: 5-6)
    - 1966-1971 (Folder 53: 7)
  - McNamara, Robert Strange, 1968 (Folder 53: 8)
  - Middle EastHistory20th century, 1938-1957 (Folder 53: 9)
  - Military conscription, 1945-1954 (Folder 53: 10)
  - Military policyUnited States (Box 54)
    - 1949-1955 (Folder 54: 1)
    - 1960-1963 (Folder 54: 2)
    - 1964-1967 (Folder 54: 3)
  - Montgomery of Alamein, Viscount, 1954-1957 (Folder 54: 4)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1972 (Folder 54: 5)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1949-1958 (Folder 54: 6)
  - Pearl Harbor (Hawaii), Attack on (1941), 1946-1961 (Folder 54: 7)
  - PhilippinesHistory20th century, 1904-1945 (Folder 54: 8)
  - Prisoners of warJapan, 1949 (Folder 54: 9)
  - Roosevelt, Archibald, 1963 (Folder 54: 10)
  - Sorge, Richard, 1949 (Folder 54: 11)
  - Soviet UnionHistory (1917-1970), 1944-1952 (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1947-1959 (Folder 55: 2)
  - Truman, Harry, 1945 (Folder 55: 3)
  - United Nations, 1962-1972 (Folder 55: 4)
  - United StatesForeign policy, 1961-1967 (Folder 55: 5)
  - United States Military Academy, West Point, 1970-1972 (Folder 55: 6)
  - VenezuelaEconomic conditions, 1962 (Folder 55: 7)
  - Vidal, Gene, 1969 (Folder 55: 8)
  - Vietnamese Conflict (1961-1975), 1968-1969 (Folder 55: 9)
  - World War (1939-1945), 1945-1946 (Folder 55: 10)
- Speeches and Writings by Others, 1935-1972. (Box 55-58)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of author
  - Ackerman, Carl W., 1936-1955 (Folder 55: 11)
  - Allen, Gary, 1968-1970 (Folder 55: 12)
  - Anderson, Tom, 1972 (Folder 55: 13)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1958-1967 (Folder 55: 14)
  - Benson, George S., 1971-1972 (Folder 55: 15)
  - Boldyreff, Constantine W.
    - undated (Folder 55: 16-17)
    - undated (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - 1955 (Folder 56: 2)
  - Brewster, Owen, undated (Folder 56: 3)
  - Brown, Constantine, 1945-1957 (Folder 56: 4)
  - Dresser, Robert B., 1965-1972 (Folder 56: 5)
  - Gill, William J., 1969-1971 (Folder 56: 6)
  - Gross, H. R., 1969-1972 (Folder 56: 7)
  - Hart, Harnell, 1951 (Folder 56: 8)
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - 1941-1950 (Folder 56: 9)
    - 1952-1960 (Folder 56: 10)
  - Hunt, Frazier (Box 57)
    - undated (Folder 57: 1)
    - 1935-1945 (Folder 57: 2)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 57: 3)
  - Kasai, Jiuji, 1945-1950 (Folder 57: 4)
  - Knerr, Hugh J., undated (Folder 57: 5)
  - Lloyd, Lewis E., 1968-1969 (Folder 57: 6)
  - Manion, Dean Clarence
    - 1954-1969 (Folder 57: 7)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 57: 8)
  - Manly, Chesly, 1966 (Folder 57: 9)
  - Mashbir, Sidney Forrester, 1953-1954 (Folder 57: 10)
  - Neumann, William L., 1957 (Folder 57: 11)
  - Root, E. Merrill
    - 1953-1965 (Folder 57: 12)
    - 1966-1971 (Folder 57: 13)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1969-1972 (Folder 57: 14)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1949-1951 (Box-folder 58: 1)
  - Tanaka Giichi, Baron, 1936 (Folder 58: 2)
  - Trohan, Walter, 1967-1970 (Folder 58: 3)
  - Wilson, Eugene E., 1942-1943 (Folder 58: 4)
- Photographs, 1946-1970. (Box 58)
  Prints, arranged by subject
  - 1 print depicting Bonner Fellers during a visit to a Boeing Aircraft Co. plant, Wichita, Kansas, undated (Folder 58: 5)
  - 2 prints depicting Bonner Fellers and Jiuji Kasai, undated (Folder 58: 6)
  - 1 print depicting Lt. Gen. William H. Tunner, undated (Folder 58: 7)
  - 1 print depicting cadets at the U.S. Air Force Academy, undated (Folder 58: 8)
  - 6 prints depicting Jiuji Kasai, 1970 May 4 (Folder 58: 9)
  - 1 print depicting an atomic explosion at Bikini atoll, 1946 July 25 (Folder 58: 10)
  - 4 prints depicting U.S. military installations, 1954 (Folder 58: 11)
  - 2 prints depicting U.S. servicemen, 1956 (Folder 58: 12)
  - 11 prints depicting U.S. Air Force planes, undated (Folder 58: 13)
  - 1 print depicting a U.S. tactical missile, undated (Folder 58: 14)
  - 2 prints depicting a plaque and a caricature, Army War College, undated (Folder 58: 15)
- Sound Recordings, 1956-1997. (Box 58-59)
  Sound tape reels and compact sound cassette, arranged by subject
  - Radio broadcast with Bonner Fellers, Manion Forum number 407, 15 July 1962; 1 open reel tapes (Box 58)
    Access
    Fellers speaks about foreign aid from the United States.
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009156
  - Paul Harvey radio programs, 1951; 1 open reel tapes (Folder 58: 17)
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009129
    Part 1: Fellers hosts the show for Paul Harvey. He talks about the Korean conflict following the dismissal of General MacArthur.
    Part 2: Paul Harvey on Wings for Peace.
  - For America rally, Carnegie Hall, New York City, 1956 February 22; 5 open reel tapes
    Part 1: Orchestra performances Part 2: Spruille Braden, Dean Clarence E. Manion, Dan Smoot
    Manion argues federalism and states' rights are the best defenses against communism. He advocates the Bricker amendment.
    Smoot talks about the growth of the federal government. He constantly makes comparisons of the United States to fascist and communist governments.
    Part 3: Dan Smoot (cont'd); William F. Buckley, Jr.; Bonner Fellers
    Part 3 technical note: this program seems to be recorded over a musical performance on the accession tape that wasn't completely erased. Buckley speaks about a variety of topics with the central theme of anticommunism. Bonner Fellers speaks about collective security and other armed forces matters.
    Part 4: Bonner Fells, Bill Jenner
    Part 5: Joseph McCarthy
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009154
    - Orchestra performance. (Folder 58: 18)
    - Speeches by Spruille Brandon, Dean Clarence Manion, and Dan Smoot (part one). (Folder 58: 19)
    - Speeches by Dan Smoot (part two), William F. Buckley, Jr., and Bonner Fellers (part one). (Folder 58: 20)
    - Speeches by Bonner Fellers (part two) and Bill Jenner. (Box-folder 58: 21)
    - Speech by Joseph McCarthy. (Folder 58: 22)
  - Radio broadcast by Bonner Fellers, "Thought War against the Kremlin Dictators,", 31 October 1958; 1 open reel tapes (Box 58)
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009155
    Bonner Fellers speaks about the Cold War and the relationship between the USA and USSR. He advocates the USA take a similar approach to the Soviet Union as it took to Japan in WWII.
  - Talk by Bonner Fellers, 3 January 1958; 1 open reel tapes (Box 59)
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009163
    Fellers speaks about NATO and collective defense. He argues the United States should be able to defend herself by herself.
  - Speech by Billy Graham, "Moral Responsibilities in the Atomic Age,", 30 April 1956; 1 open reel tapes (Box 59)
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009162
    The Rev. Dr. Billy Graham "Moral Responsibilities in the Atomic Age" First General Session - April 30, 1956 Forty-fourth Annual Meeting Chamber of Commerce of the United States
  - Recordings of a march composed by Frederick C. Mayer, "Spirit of West Point,", 9 June 1958; 2 open reel tapes (Box 59)
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009159
  - Bob Siegrist and the News radio program featuring Bill Moseley, version 1, 23 September 1963; 1 open reel tapes (Box 59)
    Siegrist speaks about the foreign relations of the United States before interviewing Moseley about missionary work in and food aid in Brazil.
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009160
  - Bob Siegrist and the News radio program featuring Bill Moseley, version 2, 23 September 1963; 1 open reel tapes (Box 59)
    Siegrist interviews Moseley about food aid to Brazil from the United States.
    This recording differs from the other recording in the collection as it does not have Siegrist's monologue at the beginning.
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009161
  - The Showa Emperor's Two Monologues, 15 June 1997; 1 audio cassette (Box 59)
    Use copy number: 70031_a_0009128
- Declassified records, 1923-1945 1945
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some materials determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2011 September release of records, 1923-1945
    - Unclassified papers, 1923-1945 (Folder 59: 8)
    - General records, 1945 (Folder 59: 9)
    - Oboe two records, 1945 (Folder 59: 10)
    - Maps and charts, 1938-1945 (Folder 59: 11)
    - Russian Liaison Mission records, 1945 (Folder 59: 12-14)
    - Southwest Pacific Area records, 1943-1945 (Folder 59: 15-16)
    - Work papers regarding Philippines occupation, 1944 (Folder 59: 17)
- Oversize materials, 1922-1968. (Box 60)
  Caricature, certificate, charts, diploma, map, print, and scrapbook, arranged chronologically
  - Travel document issued to Bonner Fellers, 1922 April 3 (Folder 60: 1)
  - "High Spots," caricature, 1933 (Folder 60: 2)
  - Print depicting students, Army War College, 1938-1939 (Folder 60: 3)
  - Two charts relating to the administration of the German economy, 1943 (Folder 60: 4-5)
  - Scrapbook relating to speeches and writings by Bonner Fellers, 1947-1953 (Folder 60: 6)
  - Map of Crete, 1947 (Folder 60: 7)
  - Diploma issued to Bonner Fellers, Sovereign Order of Saint John of Jerusalem, 1959 September 28 (Folder 60: 8)
  - Honorary certificate issued to Bonner Fellers, U.S. Congress, 1968 September 16 (Folder 60: 9)